it looks like
the build-off is taking itself to new
heights
if you didn't see the end of like whoa
whoa whoa whoa excuse me again
this seems to be a non-stop problem
oh man oh man
oh
this is absolutely ridiculous
okay for as long as i burn this guy
shouldn't be any issues oh man
this is getting really annoying
well
hello my name is korean
and for some reason i'm vibrating again
uh welcome back to another episode of
hermitcraft this girl was watching me
battle them you could have helped scar
anyway as i was saying the build-off has
escalated it's it's escalated to new
heights
but i'm not sure that this can count i
mean there are no rules and since there
are no rules i think that we can do
something
to knock this down a notch to knock this
down a notch and inside my house there's
my house has been taken over by concord
we
here
we're here
no well you are here not we here
no you don't get to claim my house
concorp thank you very much
but if we go inside
korean
no
no green
how
he's he's a zombie he's a zombie
oh man
not like this
hold on i did actually plan for this
eventuality i just don't know where i
put it
i'm pretty sure i had the bits that i
need for this
oh this is annoying hold on i've got an
idea let's uh
there we go
you stay there zombie green because i
believe
i'm pretty sure i had a potion of
weakness and all the things that you
need to cure a zombie with but i seem to
have lost it all right well village
agreeing i'm afraid
you're gonna have to just stay there for
a while until i can cure you
don't know how this has happened to you
clearly a zombie has got in maybe oh
maybe a baby zombie walked in when the
door was open that would make sense but
here's the thing everyone there was
another villager in here
and he's vanished along with all of the
other villagers surprise for the third
time so
i have a feeling we have a problem with
the apart from this guy
he's he's still going he's still going
and um
oh do you see that up there hold on can
i zoom in even further
uh huh
uh-huh so that's what that meant by
we here
scar
has arrived
look at that
he's looking at me directly no he's he's
there oh he knows what he's up to he's
straight up looking at me
what has gone on here scar what have you
made
hang on i think scar
isn't just
joining us in the village what's okay
what's this going what's going on here
what goes up doesn't come down in
minecraft scar 2019
but hold on hold on a second
is he
i think he is i think he's a little bit
taller than iskal's house
no way
he's joined
the fight he's joined the competition
[Laughter]
very nice scar
very very very good i'm not is this a
rocket
so the rocket
is upside down
and there's a floating island and then
he's built a house hold on what does
this say up here i'm a little scared to
go too close
see i don't think he's noticed hold on
[Laughter]
i'm so
i'm sorry scott
i'm sorry i couldn't help myself
oh man
i bet you he jumped out of his skin
right it says concorp highway no it is
concorp
it's not just scar
this is a concorde machine the concorp
guys have officially joined our little
build off by the looks of things
concorp highway in the sky i better go
and get it i better go get scar stuff oh
no he's there he's good
sorry i couldn't i couldn't help myself
ah he's given me a flower well now i
feel terrible
one of my favorite things to do in
hermitcraft is scarce car because he
just jumps honestly just jumps at
everything it's so funny this is an
amazing build by the way scar absolutely
amazing so officially we have a bit of
an issue
we have a bit of an issue
scar has got a big air gap here and so
does iskal but i think iskall actually
has a much larger
gap here than scar does
this does interrupt my plans but i'm
gonna stick to what i was gonna do
okay so my plan is to bring iskall's
house down a notch and i think they
should go since there's no rules since
there was no rule stating that he could
go up i don't see any rules stating that
i can't bring him back down so as you
can see i've got a bunch of grey
concrete
and what i thought i would do with this
grey concrete
is build an anvil and attach it
to iskall's house and drag it back down
weigh it down scar just says what goes
up doesn't come down in minecraft i'm
about to prove him wrong
and completely
bring iskal back down to earth from his
base now remember there are no rules so
there's no point getting mad at anybody
at this whole thing there are no rules
since he decided that he was going to be
cheeky and add
a big gap of him having a floating house
we are going to do the same line of
thinking to bring him back down
now this shouldn't take too long the
anvil part
but dragging that house down
well that's going to involve quite a few
hours of building i think iskall said
that that house took him eight hours to
build
so it's gonna take me likely the same
amount of time because what i'm gonna do
i'm gonna destroy it all of it and i'm
gonna build it block for block attached
to the anvil on the floor and this is
going to take a long time so
uh let's let's start a big time-lapse
shall we
it's only going to take about a minute
but i thought i'd time-lapse it anyway
obviously this takes a lot longer than
what you see in the video so i thought
i'd be clever here i said i was gonna
drag this down in my last episode and i
literally meant it but obviously in
minecraft i can't just attach an anvil
to the bottom and it will just sink to
the floor
no to make it look like that's happened
i have to recreate this every single
block of it so i thought the best way to
do this would be start from the bottom
and look up and make sure i mimic it so
that it is exactly in the same position
just a good few blocks lower to stop
iskall's cheekiness of trying to float
into the air and pretending like his
house is the tallest one when it's not
even attached to the ground but now i
think it's all fair game as i've put an
anvil on the bottom attached some chains
to it and i think it's fair to say that
from bottom to top it is one consistent
building now you don't need to thank me
scout it's okay this one's for free
it wasn't free for me though even though
i took every single block of his down
somehow i still managed to spend more
materials remaking this than i did
taking it down so something went wrong
in the calculations but there you have
it look at that
magnificent isn't it
and there we go the final thing is done
making this was a lot more difficult
than i initially thought
because this balloon well i wasn't about
to make it exactly block for block but i
did manage to count at least the shape
size so it's exactly the same height 15
blocks tall and then it goes five blocks
out in each direction so it is the same
size it's just not exactly the same
composition however
i still think it looks relatively the
same it's a big ball of wool and
despite my best efforts i've attached an
anvil to the bottom i think you know to
be fair i had to give a reason why i've
dragged this island down and i have
attached an anvil to the bottom so that
gravity can do its thing
but it actually hasn't made that much
difference to the height difference
so it looks like it's just a couple of
blocks taller
than the very tip
of this
whatever this is
whatever this thing is it looks like a
slime block machine whatever this is
iskall is still strictly speaking
winning on this side but now scars house
is winning on this oh this this is
getting a bit complicated so that was
basically only part one
i needed to bring iskall's house down
if i was going to have a chance
of winning in the long run because
i felt like the big gap there was giving
him such an advantage but i feel like
the the playing field has been leveled
somewhat and scar on the same merit has
also got the same thing but there's no
there's no way
i am remaking this and making it go down
again so hopefully scar will just stay
there for now and he's not gonna
properly join the competition
but part two has to begin where
i
well i'm gonna have to make my house
even bigger than all of this
and scars remember i only need to be one
block taller and that will do the trick
but that looks way more even in my
opinion look the top of this house
is in line with almost the top of the
platform and the top of my house the
balloon is the thing that's given him
a major advantage but we're about
to
set the record straight on who has the
biggest house but while i was doing that
and that took such a long time i was uh
trying to make it as exact as possible
taking every block and just moving it
down i also happen to find
the healing potion well actually the
potion of weakness to to heal this guy
which is um
villager green there he is now i've
never done this before so i'm a little
bit scared but i believe
oh please tell me that him and then
i think that's it and now he should turn
into a villager no
i gave him a golden apple i gave you a
golden apple
why isn't he changing back
i don't think the shaking is part of the
healing process it's like he's got the
shivers like he's just taken a potion
that's making him better but i i don't
know i think maybe we have to just wait
it out
there's still red particles around him
so until those red particles go away i'm
still thinking that this is working i've
never done this before
and it probably won't be the last
my goodness it worked but he lost his
head
and his name tag oh no oh no no no he's
still he's still called green it's just
hidden but he's definitely lost his head
and he's also changed professions now
it's been totally reset and he's giving
me such a good deal this is such a good
deal okay so that obviously
quite strangely resets some things but
he is still village agree and
technically speaking fortunately i keep
a stock of my own head you never know
when you're gonna need a stock of your
own head
it's come on come in useful more than
once we've cured you but now we need to
make you right are you ready villager
green there we go everything is right
with the world
now that that's out of the way i need to
continue with this rather lengthy task
of becoming the the best and biggest
house in sahara street well i guess it's
beyond sahara street now i think it's
an entire hermitville and i've got to
i've got to build more of this higher
and higher and higher and higher i still
haven't quite finished some of these
things now i probably could have
improved the shape on this a little bit
but it just needs to make sure that it
is 100 lit up in here that's the main
thing so there's no
no zombie spawning
and on iskals he had a bunch of end rods
on the bottom here so i'm just going to
make sure that i've i'm going to add
that probably not the best way to do
this
because these are like oh no
there we go that should do it
that provides the little bit of like i
think they're like the strings to some
of the balloons i'm not entirely sure
but i just want to make sure that most
of the build is pretty much the same it
looks a little bit more like a hot air
balloon but overall i ended up using
more wool than was there originally so
yes it's not exactly the same but
i'm pretty sure that looks good that
looks that looks nice it looks roughly
the same
and it's still the tallest house but not
for much longer so
let's start building
this now i really need to think very
carefully about how i'm going to tackle
this
because
it's already a pretty delicate operation
at the moment i could attach something
here or i could go from here it's gonna
be
yeah it's gonna be difficult it's gonna
be difficult
either way i've prepared about as much
spruce as i can and what i might do
is what i did last time which is make
the actual shape of the build and then
detail it at another time so i'll get
all the shape down and get the height
and then next episode i can detail it so
let's begin
right we're doing another time lapse
obviously this video was set into two
parts bringing a scout's house down and
then building mine up
that doesn't happen very often that i do
two really long time lapses of course
they're not long to you they're long for
me so what i've decided to do is build
up the house exactly the same style as
before but what i didn't realize was
i had a quite a long way to go i thought
i was doing quite well so i kind of
worked from the top and the bottom at
the same time to try and meet them in
the middle because i knew i only had to
get one block taller i thought i could
sort of cheat a little bit by using just
a really big tower in the middle so that
i didn't have to build too much of the
houses and like all the different parts
of it all over the place so i only just
had to tip the very top of it over the
edge and it worked out quite well and
i'm gonna detail that later on
i may have just finished this time lapse
but uh ren has decided to go afk and
immediately i didn't even say anything
to impulse but both of us at the same
time made this
and um
there we go
now all we have to do is add a little
button
oh no
oh no i forgot
i forgot
[Music]
he's back
well it didn't go exactly to plan
this aggression will not stand man this
must be really annoying for him though
he can see and now he can't
oh you got you must know never to go afk
especially in hermitville there's so
many people here
well now that that's done take a look at
this now obviously the detailing's not
done that takes extra hours but i spent
a good amount of time making this and
it was a lot taller than i thought it
needed to be and that was because my
plans got a bit scuppered by scars but
if you check this out it is taller even
if it doesn't look like it so standing
on this this is 1 6 2 on the y
coordinate 162 blocks high
and mine is if i can
i almost managed to land on it
and mine is
163 and a half because it is a fence
block so i am one and a half blocks
taller than the other well the current
leader which is scar so i now currently
hold the position of biggest house on
sahara street or in hermitville on the
server
and it only took me
six hours straight of building bringing
iskall's house down a notch which took
forever and then building mine up i
still think mine could do with a few
improvements but
oh my goodness this is amazing i think
my favorite angle for this
is this side i think it just works
really really well i don't know i think
maybe this middle bit's too
centralized i should have made it go off
to the side and have it like dangling i
might change it up a little bit when i
detail it but i think that is more than
enough building for now this is a
project that has gone a little bit out
of hand it really has and i also think
i also think that
we should do something to stop mumbo
because this is clearly gonna launch
and i don't know if that counts but
i don't know what else we can do we
could try and stop him
but my house is too far away i should
have built it like steadily over and
over and over and
lent over the side there maybe i'll do
that in my next episode i'll sort of
bring it over i mean this could be just
one peak if i need to go taller which
i'm sure it will i what i'll do is i'll
just extend it this way and then i'll
block mumbos and then it'll stop even
higher there you know what that is
definitely what's gonna happen because
we're gonna have to start planning ahead
for this with scar here with iskal
he's going to want revenge
this is going to be a build-off that i
don't think anyone saw coming but the
stakes have never been higher i don't
know what the stakes are but
well the houses are the houses are the
houses have never been higher but either
way we currently hold the top spot
and my goodness do i need a break from
hermitville now the villagers may be
gone again but i have secured one
villager in there and i just need to
find another one that survived the purge
put them in there too
and then i can start repopulating the
village again
it's these patrols we saw at the start
of the video they're everywhere but
either way i want to pop back to the old
lands real quick mainly because i know
that some people have been trying out my
elytra course and i want to make sure
that i've still got the top spot
nobody is taking the did you die box
people have been going oh this is
brilliant how many
diamonds
31 diamonds and some rocket sails
33 diamonds on this project
that's probably more diamonds than i've
made on other projects remember i
invested
just a lot of time into making this i
didn't invest a huge amount of diamonds
i invested a lot of diamonds into the
did you die boxes i don't know if i'm
ever gonna break even on these but this
has just been time and oh look at the
diamonds i think i'm going to keep them
there just because i kind of want to see
how many times people will play the
course i still have the best score so
far and no one else has put up their
score meaning they've probably not done
particularly well
so hopefully a few more people will try
it out i want someone to come along and
beat me and then i'm going to try and
top that but i don't want to sit here
making the best score i mean that was my
first run and it's still holding up
pretty strong so i'm interested to see
how people do
but i'm afraid that that is definitely
enough for today's episode i have been
building literally all day i am very
very tired
i want to say thank you very much for
watching everyone i hope you enjoyed
today's episode and
well we'll just see what happens next
with this gigantic sahara street
build-off
my next plan is to get sahara open
thanks again for watching
what is this vibration
it's a i don't know what it is it's i
think it's
it's got to be something to do with f5
now is it just every time it is
goodbye